<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Forgotten on neon•Golem</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/forgotten/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Forgotten on neon•Golem</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/forgotten/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Forgotten gods of Atheros 4</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/writing/forgotten_gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/writing/forgotten_gods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The sunset is breathtaking today. A dense fog rises from the moors as the heat of the day dissipates into the crystal clear autumn night. The sky is painted a vibrant orange. The chroma today is a vivid pink – a rare occurrence.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Stillness. I stand at the edge of a forest looking down on the lowlands. I wonder if you, too, once saw this. Emerging from the treelines is my silent companion. An ancient skeleton of a creature of impossible size. Towering above the wildlands, this is not the only one. The entire planet is filled with them. They stand guard by the forests, forests no doubt more ancient than themselves. This one takes the shape of a humanoid. Just the torso - it towers above me many, many times my height. The forgotten gods of Atheros 4. Who were they? What happened to them? Why are they all watching over the forests? One thing remains certain. The wildlife avoids their gaze, so this will be my camp for the night. The subconscious tells me to run like hell and not look back. The rational thought in me, however, tells me this is safe. And I am a man of science.&#xA;The fog curls and thickens as the light dies; each breath tastes faintly of cold loam and resin. Under the ribs of that titan, shadows fold like curtains. Its bones are not white so much as the pale grey of weathered stone, threaded with moss and fern that pulse faintly in the last light. The wind from the moors gust, making the vertebrae sing — a low, hollow chord that sounds almost like a language.&#xA;I make camp beneath its chest — a shallow hollow, smelling of sap and moist. A fox pauses at the tree-line before vanishing, the tail bouncing above the foliage before disappearing into the darkness. The subconscious prickles: the posture of a thing built to watch is not the posture of a thing that forgets. Yet there is no motion, only the slow settling of the night. Rational thought counts the reasons it’s safe: massive, inert, decayed. The other voice counts the reasons it is not: those who stand still can listen.&#xA;The questions pull at me. Were these guardians built to protect the forests? Or do they intend to keep something in?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The old one watches with a silence that feels like a held ledger. I crouch beneath its chest andspeak the words. “What are you trying to tell me” I do not expect an answer, but the air  itself insists on being addressed. For a time there is nothing but the wind folding over heather.&#xA;When the moss along the sternum moves it does so without hurry: a single, measured swell as if the creature is inhaling centuries. It makes a sound. A soft whisper, more like punctuation rather than words. The fox at the tree line re-emerges for a second, curious, then becomes a shadow again. I feed the embers with a handful of dry bark and let the light trace the old ribs into black script. The moor is patient. So I wait.&#xA;The old ones as I call them. To study them is my objective. I am not permitted to leave this world until I have answers. These creatures, unnerving as they are, have not interfered with my goals. Their still gaze follows me - this much I can tell. What for? The woods that they guard, they hold no big mystery. There are remnants of a civilization, but it is far newer than they themselves are. If this torso is in fact a whole creature, then half of its’ length is buried beneath. Do i have to dig for what i seek? The thought fills me with dread. Unnatural dread. It is almost as if this is how the old ones talk. They breathe as the wind plays with the decay, the appendages of nature attempting to reclaim them. On the outside, there is nothing but stillness. This realm is inviting, it holds an abundance of resources, the woods have sustained me for the long weeks and months that I’ve roamed these lands. Yet I cannot shake the feeling that all of this is wrong This world of Atheros 4 is entirely too quiet. Too perfect, too accommodating, too eerie. It is uncanny. Do they communicate through emotion? But this would imply things. That they know what I’m after. I am being steered, clearly. But where to? How do they expect me to react? I look up at my silent companion. Indeed, what are you trying to tell me?&#xA;No matter. I have become part of the system that the old ones operate. My curiosity is a variable. The system adjusts. The night is long.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I awake before dawn with a strange satisfaction and pack up camp. This world is vast and full of opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
