<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Time on neon•Golem</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/time/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Time on neon•Golem</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/time/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A seedling of time</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/writing/liminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/writing/liminal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Theres a stillness in the air. The weather can best be described as sticky. The sun, belting down on me relentlessly. It feels like time itself has stopped. Silence. Ahh, there it is. I’ve felt this way before. I can hear the faint sound of crows in the distance.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The year is 1996 and I’m about to enter first grade. Except I’m 36, the year is 2025 and it is a Sunday. Both of these are true. Both of these &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; true. It’s as if I’ve stepped through the fold, crossed the veil, to a bygone era, yet remained firmly planted in the present. It feels like a lifetime ago. The weight of the years is tangible.&#xA;I’m staring down an empty parking lot, watching the heat haze in the air. I’m basking in this sensation, I’m absorbing it. It is a strange feeling of nostalgia. One that isn’t tied to a specific memory, but to the &lt;em&gt;texture of existence itself&lt;/em&gt;. I’ve been here before. I’ve felt this in the past. The soviet era buildings. The cracks in the pavement. The trees to the side, stretching their roots into the concrete, bulging, cracking, forcing their way through.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The stillness. The crushing stillness that somehow inspires comfort. It invokes emptiness yet familiarity. It makes you feel like you’re alone in the world, yet it feels cozy. Like watching hand drawn anime on a VHS tape.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A temporal shift. Two realities colliding, bleeding into one another, meshing and fusing into one.  It is the emptiness of the moment that gives it this liminal feeling. On the boundary of time itself, neither here nor there. This feeling, this rift in time and space, it holds endless potential. A seedling, of time. Could I do it?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A car rolls into the parking lot. The spell is broken. I solidify in reality once more. Damn. This time was close. Too close. So close I could almost touch it. I was almost there. Why though? What am I chasing? A second chance maybe? A means to redo everything? All of it?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I chuckle. I already know the answer. I know exactly how this would pan out. I would painstakingly gouge my deepest memories. I would follow the traces, the breadcrumbs. I would execute the plan to the letter. All of it, exactly the same. All of it, so that I could make the exact same choices. Smoke the exact brand of cigarettes, drink the same beer and take the exact same taxi to the exact same, wrong address. Lose my keys at the exact day, crash my bike on the same intersection. I would repeat everything, do it all the same to a tee, all in the hopes of meeting you one, more time. It was magical. All of it. A second chance? A life lived without regret does not ask for a second chance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
